特坎姆先生
Chief Metacomet.
没有您父亲的帮忙
Without
我们谁也活不过第一个冬天
your father's friendship, none of us could have survived.
我父亲应该让你们
My father should have let you
去死!
die!
你是
You are
唯一
the only one
е坦\之心
who comes to us
碚椅的人.
with an open heart.
可你的人用e言
But your people have murdered
\⒘
my father
我的父H!
with their lies!
我叫珠.
My name is Pearl.
@故事是P於我的母H, 海z特・白m因.
This is the story of my mother, Hester Prynne.
那是在1666年,
It was the year of our Lord 1666,
她到_了RT海岸殖民地
when she arrived in the Massachusetts Bay Colony
M心希望在@Y，在@新世界Y
filled with the hope that at last, in this new world
能蜃罱K自由的信仰，而]有恐趾推群
would come the freedom to worship without fear of persecution.
我尊敬的同僚!
My esteemed colleague!
多年的辛苦你更健康了!
Thy years of toil become thee!
久仰您的大名，先生.
Thy fame preceeds thee, sir.
`h督,
Governor Bellingham,
允S我介B
may I present
托R斯・奇夫牧.
the Reverend Thomas Cheever.
g迎您先生. 一路辛苦了.
Welcome, sir. It's a long voyage.
海上三月,
3 months at sea,
要NZ走你的信仰, 要N使它杂踩玷F.
will either take away your faith, or harden it to iron.
`h督 允S我向您介B一位c我同行的女士
Allow me to introduce a woman who's been travelling with us,
海z特・白m因夫人
- Mistress... - Hester Prynne.
原我@p
I apologize for the coarseness
粗糙的手, 夫人.
of my hands, Mistress.
不^@Y是殖民地, l都得只.
But here in the colonies, everyone must work.
我渴望繁重的工作,督.
I look forward to the hard work.
就像《fs》92篇中所的: "我⒖孔约旱碾p手 取得倮".
It says id Psalm 92: "I will triumph in the work of thy hands".
]想道您引用}.
Thou canst quote the Scriptures.
是的，牧，fs和新s 我丈夫教我的
Aye, Reverendo, both Testaments. My husband taught me.
您得休息了，奇夫牧.
You must rest.
然後，我很意您⒂^我的成就
Then I'll show you what's been accomplished.
非常感x.
I thank thee.
- 哦，@是白m因太太. - 是的，是的.
- Then it's Goodwife Prynne. - Yes, yes.
不^我更喜ge人叫我海z特.
But I prefer to be called Hester.
g迎你, 海z特.
Welcome, Hester.
要是能跟著第一批磉@憾嗪,
I wish I could've seen it before,
r是原始的荒U之地
when it was wild and untouched.
太太,
Madam,
在@地方 少禳cb更好.
you should use less lace in your dressmaking.
然, 牧.
Indeed, Reverend.
全能的上帝啊,
Master of us all,
感x您再次慷慨地n予我食物
we give thanks for another bountiful meal,
感x@些新到_的信徒,
and for newly arrived disciples,
c我分享此宴.
that share it with us this night.
- 阿T. - 阿T.
- Amen. - Amen.
督先生.
So, Governor.
我迫不及待地想知道 你和特坎姆判的情r.
I am impatient to know how you fared with Metacomet.
哦，特坎姆不是_索米，姆上校.
Well, Metacomet isn't Massassoit, Major Dunsmuir.
但我相信如果我遵守c他父H之g的fh
But if we respect the agreements we made with his father,
就]什N可怕的
we've nothing to fear.
英名的上帝怕我
So we don't grow complacent,
得意忘形
our wise God sends us a sign.
所以下了神I
When we sailed,
督先生，我在信上看到你f我c野人和平相.
your letters said we were at peace with the savage.
哦,
Well,
跟帕Z人所^的和平日子就要到^了
I fear the days of "peace" with the Wampanoag is at an end.
少校,
Major,
我著@些新淼娜肆
we are frightening our new arrival.
我在家常f你
We hear much
印第安人皈依我主
of your success with the praying Indians.
我非常渴望拜丁梅斯黛牧
I'm very eager to meet Reverend Dimmesdale
和他的皈依者
and his converts.
那一C侏儒
The runts of the litter.
丁梅斯黛是小
Dimmesdale's little treasures!
我有些人有不同看法
Some of us have other opinions.
白m因太太,
Mistress Prynne,
我希望你能跟我住在@
I hope you'll stay with us
等你丈夫到了再f
until your husband's arrival.
你可真好，斯D赫太太 不^我想
You're most kind, but I intend to find
自己找到房子，越快越好
a house of my own as soon as possible.
你自己住
On thine own?
是的
Why, yes.
在@阂年p女人自己住可不好
It's not considered fitting for a young woman to live alone.
可是我丈夫吩咐我先找好住所等著他
I've come first to prepare a place for his arrival,
所以我想先找房子
so that is what I intend to do.
白m因太太
Mistress Prynne.
我的生活定也Sπ碚M了些
The rules we live by may seem arbitrary to a newcomer,
不^我有K痛的教
but we have learnt the hard way
如果在@]有栏竦囊定
that without absolute order,
就o法生存
we cannot hope to survive here.
定, 白m因太太
Rules, Mistress Prynne.
有序.
Order.
才能生存.
Survival.
你是想要我`抗丈夫的意思
Would you have me disobey my husband?
- 我…… - 奇夫牧, 你也S意
- I... - Reverend, you might enjoy
我鹤优隳阕。他叫布斯特
the company of my son, Brewster.
在大WW^神W
He studied Divinity.
哈佛不m合他
Harvard wasn't good enough for him,
所以他只好回家……
so he came home to make his fortune as a...
一般牧的孩子睡X的r候
Minister's sons all moaning the Lord's Prayer
嘴Y嘟著\告~
in their sleep.
每人都得有自己的位置.
Everyone must find his place.
- 早上好, 白m因太太 - 早上好.
- Morning, Mistress Prynne. - Good morrow.
你到@硎遣皇窍胝兴的反感
So you intend on scandalising the town!
{
Get up!
很好
Good!
我很
I confess,
我倦了唯唯ZZ的生活
I feel alone in a sea of conformists.
我哪洪_始找
Where should we begin our search?
海的已律
On the cliffs by the sea.
不，那可不行
No, it's out of the question.
槭颤N？
Why?
波`被印第安人消绲粢葬
No one's lived by the sea
就]有人住在海了
since the Indians wiped out Ballinger's Point.
我就哪洪_始
I say we start there.
那就你的吧，白m因太太
Well, if you've decided.
布斯，那就是?
Is that it, Brewster?
哦，太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
我o法想像
I tried to imagine what herlife was like
她淼竭@盒率澜缰前的生活
before she came to the new world.
她丈夫槭颤N要她一人
Why did herhusband send heron ahead,
先
alone?
是榱丝简她的忠\
Was it a test ofherloyalty,
是她的精神
orherspirit?
也S@是她丈夫本性的一面
Or was it in his nature to set traps
O置陷阱，希望人能掉M
forpeople in the hope they would fall into them?
好O了
It's perfect!
一v加一把好就能安家
With a cart and a musket, I could have a home here!
，R
A cart, a horse,
草叉子，犁
a pitchfork, a plow.
我能想出很多更好的事
I can think of better things
@p漂亮的手去做 而不是它LO
to do with these pretty hands than grow calluses on them.
我需要契s工，至少得
I'll need indentured labor, at least two men.
- @K地需要排浪 - 你真B固，白m因太太
- The land needs draining. - You are headstrong.
也S@是天生的
Perhaps it runs in the blood.
我f您父H就是@脾
I'm told your father was too.
他是不是……
Is it true
真的欠你丈夫的就拿你眄
he was in debt to your husband and you were the payment?
哦，@你不高d了
I've said something to disturb you.
Σ黄
I'm sorry.
真Σ黄
I'm truly sorry.
哦，上帝，你真是太美了
God, thou art wondrous fair!
真疼
That hurt!
好，@提醒你e再@N做
Good. It'll remind you not to do it again.
菲z？ 普D斯？
Faith? Prudence?
你f了]有？白m因太太有浴盆
Did you hear Mistress Prynne has a bathing tub?
她是哪人？法人？
What is she, French?
上攘睿 你意出上攘幔上攘
2 Shillings. Will you bid 2 shillings?
半先令，半先令
2 and a half?
注意先生 意出半先令幔
Come on, gentlemen, do I have a bid for 3 shillings?
哦，到三先令了
3 shillings?
F在是三先令
有多出
Anyone else? Anyone else?
好，成交
Going for 3 shillings. Any other bids?
三先令uo那位先生
Sold to the gentleman for 3 shillings.
- 下面我要拍u的@是 - 那
- Next we have this other one, - Those two.
他的契s有多久？
How much time left on their indenture?
大s三年
About 3 years, but,
不^是你丈夫或者你父H跟我生意不是
shouldn't your husband or father be doing business with me?
我的X您看不上，先生？
Is my money no good to you, sir?
您的X如同光下的美酒，太太
Your money's as fine as wine in the sunshine, Mistress.
如果您出的rX公道 Ъt巾的女孩就送o你了
If you buy them at a just price, I'll throw in the girl in red.
她是奴`
She's a slave!
她不f，@是麻，天生就那
But she don't speak, if that be a problem. Born that way.
你就_r吧
Name your just price.
您要是去林子，最好有我陪著，太太
We'd best accompany you if your going to the forest.
不用心，U比先生 我走不h
Don't worry Mr Bobbin. I shan't go far.
白m因太太? 白m因太太?
Mistress Prynne? Mistress Prynne?
白m因太太?
Mistress Prynne?
你在哪?
Where are you?
白m因太太, 你在哪?
Mistress Prynne, where are you?
是我找到她的
I found her.
- 不是你找到的 - 是我找到的
- You did not. - I did to.
- 你]有 - 是我
白m因太太,
Mistress Prynne,
y道你忘了幔拷裉焓前蚕⑷
Have you forgotten it is the Sabbath?
然]有，原
Of course not. Forgive me.
我特意你去教堂
We've come by especially to bring you to church.
太感x了
Thank you, so much.
不用管我
Please, go on without me.
我R上跟著你去
I will follow at once.
抓o吧
Make haste.
好的，先生
Yes, sir.
好吧，姑娘
All right, girl,
戆
Come on.
使
Oh goodnes!
後退，後退
Back up. Back up.
戆桑後退
Come on now, back up.
快c，退後，退後
Come on. Come on. Back up.
早上好
Good morrow.
要我湍幔
May I be of assistance?
不下碓觞N
Not from up there.
戆桑後退
Come on.
後退呀
Come on. Steady. Steady.
好像我]法它懂我的
I can't make this horse understand me.
恚我
Let me try.
戆桑姑娘
Come on, girl.
用力，後退
Come on, back up!
使牛使
Come on, girl.
姑娘，使
Come on. Come on.
恐怕陷得太深了
I'm afraid you're in too deep.
]k法上 我抬一下
She'll not make it. Let me try this.
你能把它抬出砭秃昧
I do hope you can get it free.
Y拜x式我s不上了 大家肯定在f三道四
I'm already late for the service, and everyone's talking about me.
不如躲得hh的 不在乎他的流言蜚Z
I've been away and I'm quite behind on local gossip.
我在波`I了套f房子
I bought the old Newbury place out on Ballinger's Point.
嗯
Then,
我向你道歉
I owe you an apology.
我一直在冒犯你
I've been trespassing.
那有地方，我在那合丛
There's a place at the point where I like to bath.
真的？我不收你太高的
Really? Well, I shan't charge too steep a tariff.
使殴媚铮往後退
Come on, girl, back up!
- 使 - 一,
- Back up. - One,
二,
Two,
二， 三
Two. Three.
恐怕@得陷到下安息日了
I'm afraid this cart will be stuck here until Sabbath next
除非我找些人兔
unless I gather hands to help.
介意跟我T一匹R幔
Would you care to ride with me?
跟你坐在一起？
On your horse, with you?
Γ除非你TR
Aye, unless you can ride.
我T
I can ride.
好，你T我的R，我T你的
You take my horse and I'll take yours.
有一l近路，去R合c
There's a shortcut to the meeting house,
不^不太好走
but it's a difficult road.
我能行，先生
I shall manage, sir.
- 你肯定幔 - 你路吧
- Are you certain? - Just you lead the way.
{！{！
Come on! Come on!
上帝c你同在
May God be with you.
我相信已同在了
I'm sure he already is.
可是你不去
But aren't you coming to...
安息日平安
Good Sabbath to ye all.
朋友
Friends,
Mゴ粝氲
and fellow voyagers,
同舟共的同事
in the greatest of all dreams.
我如同^去的 以色列人被挑x出
We've been singled out, like Israel of old,
作榈涔
to serve as a model.
所以如果能成功地
But if we are to succeed
建立我新的耶路撒冷
in building our new Jerusalem,
我的新的}城
our "City on a Hill",
那鄣牧α
then the power of love,
是的，上帝的
yea, His Divine Love,
我必f一心
we must bind our hearts as one!
英人和印第安人
English and Indian,
F族和契s工 自由人和奴`
gentry and indentured, free man and slaves,
⒔立一
and make of us
令全世界Q奇的榜
an example for all the world,
然後宣Q
to marvel at and proclaim:
@
"Here...
才是M善M美的
is the measure of perfection!
@
Here,
@是上帝的意旨
lives God's own!"
可我]有通^@一z
But we are not succeeding in that test.
我失× 槭颤N？
We are failing! And why?
因槲婪o度
Because we covet, nay,
我奢求我凫段的|西
we lust after what is not ours.
我奢求印第安人富的土地
Be it for the rich land of our Indian brothers,
奢求su
be it for glory,
奢求利益，奢求
for profits or for revenge.
需要我f出每人的
Need I read the secret
心
of every heart?
好，你需要我就f
I will if you want.
你需要我就f
Yea, I will if you want.
我把你心中的秘密
I will lay open the secrets
敞_於上帝的面前
before the eyes of God!
任何婪者都是我橙 上帝@诱f
What thou lusteth after is my enemy, sayeth the Lord God.
只有我能M足你
For only I shall consume thee,
也能缒
only I shall fill thee up.
如果你`背我的意旨
If thou failest to heed my commandments,
那我的拳^
then my fist
⑷缡^一勇湓谀的身上
shall descend on thee like a stone!
而且我的把你切成肉泥
And thy sword shall cut thee into bloody parts,
甚至你的也
and even thy memories shall be sacrificed
永hSL而去
to the winds for all time!
上帝保佑你
May God bless you,
保佑每一人
each and every one of you.
阿T
Am.
阿瑟，你允S我介B一位新加入}的女士
Allow me to present a newcomer to our congregation,
_堋ぐ滋m因太太
Mistress Roger Prynne.
_芴太？
Mistress Roger?
她的丈夫，一位大名鼎鼎的t生就要砗退F聚了
Aye, her husband, a renowned physician will join her before...
丁梅斯黛牧和我已……
Reverednd Dimmesdale and I have already...
我瓦^白m因太太 她的R在森林Y陷住了
I helped when her cart got stuck in the woods.
我非常喜g你的布道
I greatly enjoyed your sermon.
如此年p面演vr又如此激情四射，真是y得
It's rare for a man so young to speak with such passion.
是的，不知道槭颤N
For some reason,
我今天非常有激情
I felt most inspired today.
g迎您和您的丈夫加入我}
We welcome you and your husband to our congregation.
！！
Mother! Mother!
哦，你在@, 海z特.
There you are, Hester.
我的朋友R尼・莫斯，小W校L
Meet my friend, Running Moose. He's our schoolmaster.
想睃cc心幔
And I'm sure you'd like some refreshment.
哦，是的 你也教英孩子幔R尼・莫斯先生
Do you teach the English children as well Mr Running Moose?
在@核都叫我s翰或s翰尼
They call me John or Johnny here.
我M力教，不^英人D的有c慢
We try our best, but the English are a bit slow-witted.
D得慢？
Slow-witted?
s翰尼坶_玩笑 他是我的第一印第安信徒
Johnny's a bit of a jester, but he was our first praying Indian.
@位是我最好的朋友
My best friend in the colony.
阿瑟
Arthur,
- @位是…… - 我^面了
- this is Mistress... - We've already met.
Σ黄
Excuse me.
@禾像家了
So like home.
不^那些涞尼崦 想必是一片野U之地
Yet beyond those trees I suspect a savagery,
充M野性
of savage passions,
黑暗和未Z服
dark and untamed.
哦，丁梅斯黛牧 ^我年p的朋友了幔
Reverend Dimmesdale, have you met our young friend?
是的，我^了
Yes, we've met.
白m因太太和我是坐同一l船淼
Mistress Prynne and I traveled out on the same ship.
砦乙嫁o他
I'm going to marry him one day.
你]上嘴，我才要嫁o他 幔堪滋m因太太？
No you're not, I'm going to aren't I Mistress Prynne?
- 嫁ol -然是丁梅斯黛牧了
- Marry whom? - Reverend Dimmesdale, of course!
"ゴ蟮淖罱K判日述".
"A Short Description of the Great and Last Judgement".
哦, "教堂戒律".
Well, "Platform for Church Discipline".
都是些小宰
They're all tracts!
"主D…… "
"The Goodwife's Manual... "
"主D用游镲B手"
for Animal Husbandry"
我相信我^了
I believe we've already met.
哦，是的，ΓΓΣ黄 我……
Oh, yes, I... I'm sorry, I didn't realize.
不，不，不，我先打招呼
I should have announced my presence.
你在看什N
What are you reading?
- "c祝神", 作者是…… - s翰・密D
- "Comus", it's by John - John Milton.
知道，我x^
I know it. I've read it.
你x^？
Have you?
是的，我在家不只洗洗涮涮
I'm not all counterpanes and coverlets.
只要有空我就xc什N的
Every spare moment, I read.
我也一
I'm the same.
@房子Y的我都看^ 有些x^妆榱
I've read every book in this room. Some of them several times.
"主D游镲B手"你也x^幔
Even "Manual for Animal Husbandry?"
x得最高d的一本
A most exhiliarating read.
你真的喜g我的布道幔
So, did you truly enjoy my sermon?
是的，很喜g，非常有技巧
Yes, it was most skilful.
@然社δ惴浅Ｆ髦
Clearly your congregation reverences you.
你不喜g,我@是世界的 @然_不到你敦的水
You liked it not. We don't come up to London standards.
正好相反，我被你的激情感樱我f^
To the contrary. I was moved by your passion.
而且
And?
什N？
Well,
你的手第一次]拥r候
when your fist struck your hand,
像把σ^空
and sliced through the air like a sword,
我r就在想
I found myself wondering
你如此激情的演v後面藏著多大的痛苦啊
what manner of pain lay beneath such forceful oratory.
你真是口o遮r，白m因太太
Your tongue knows no rules, Mistress Prynne.
如果真有痛苦，牧
And if it did, Reverend,
那布道又有什N用
what purpose would it serve?
我J槿知的上帝
And here I thought comprehending God
成槲易畲蟮奶
was to be my greatest challenge.
怎N了，牧？
Yes, Reverend?
今天早上在森林Y
This morning in the forest,
槭颤N不f你已Y婚了？
why did you not say you were married?
槭颤N不f你是牧？
Why did you not say you were a minister?
再, 白m因太太
Good day, Mistress Prynne.
您好, 白m因太太
Good morrow, Mistress Prynne.
您好
Good morrow.
想肀O果酒幔
You care for a cup of cider?
我好像是居
We are your neighbours, it seems.
喜g今天上午的布道幔
Did you like the sermon this morning?
我坐在那嚎吹侥懵得挺高d的
From where I sat it seemed it did please thee.
我非常喜g
I liked it very much.
我想那位年p的牧很……
I thought the young minister very...
英俊？
Handsome?
哈里森・希本斯
Harriet Hibbons.
戆
Ruth?
你好
How do you do?
硪]被邀去⒓
Come and meet some of the others who were not invited
督家小舞的人
to the Governer's shindig.
莎琳・肖特, 白m因太太
Sally Short, Mistress Prynne.
您好
How do you do?
您到的r候我在a^上
I was on the dock when you arrived.
・R林斯
Mary Rollins.
哦，不大喜gf
Mary don't like to speak much.
[了那些野U人的mp不到半年多
She's only been free from the savages this half year.
有莫特娜，她不信任英人，
And Matona don't trust the English, do you dear?
幔坑H鄣
Mistress Prynne?
xx您 不，我不喝酒
Thank you, no. I never imbibe.
看起恚您收集了一些上好的草
You've gathered some fine Balm of Gilead,
牧羊人X包，蓍草
Shepherd's Purse, yarrow.
您JR@些草
You know your plants?
是的，我可以背b典
I do. I recite "Culpepper" by heart.
真的？
Really?
要是乐氐用什Nt治
Then what would you use to heal a bad burn?
我^甜洋草的奇效
I've seen sweet fern work miracles,
不^典建h用黑莓和t血松
but Culpepper suggests blackberry and red cedar.
哦，你了
Well, you hear that.
我X得非常幸\，我丈夫有一大房
My husband has a very large library
我可以自己找去看
and I was able to school myself.
喜g我的新}地幔
How do you like our new Jerusalem?
你X得太C穆了？
Sober enough for you?
Aye,
太C穆了
sober enough.
我是想念舞啊
What I miss is the dancing.
舞？
Dancing?
我淼r候
When first we came,
他都著五朔柱跳舞
they'd be dancing round the maypole.
^的r候都唱y七八糟的歌
Feast days we'd sing bawdy songs.
人那r候不怕出h
People weren't afraid to play the fool.
我能教熊跳舞
We'd teach the bears to dance.
F在，人的色越碓匠猎碓侥
Now days, everybody getting more and more sourfaced and ponderous.
原淼奈逅分成了鞭打柱
And a whipping post stands where the mayppole used to be.
只有我]有忘怎N笑， 幔抗媚
But there's a few of us who haven't forgotten to laugh.
能到你我非常高d
It's been a pleasure meeting you all.
我很不情告o
I'm sorry I must take my leave,
可我必走了，我可不想在夜Y陷在@森林Y
but I don't want to be stuck in the wilds at night.
@我起砗芷婀
There are things that sound to me,
夜g的荒野是我的I地
the wilds at night are my natural territory.
尤其在月A之夜
Particulary when there's a full moon.
您想用咒Z唬我
Do you try to frighten me with this witch talk?
不, 白m因太太
Not so, Mistress Prynne.
可我能看到e人看不到的|西
But I can see what others cannot.
@然是咒Z
Be a curse, to be sure,
我能x懂人的心
but I know the hearts of men.
我的心告V你什N？
And what does my heart tell you?
你是漂亮女人，白m因太太
You're a most comely woman.
男人心m然能握到少女的手
Let a man tremble who wins the hand of a maid,
可得不到它心中的全部激情
but possesses not the full passion of her heart.
我丈夫]有什N可怕的
My husband has nothing to fear.
再，希本斯太太
Good day Mistress Hibbons.
再, 白m因太太
Good day, Mistress Prynne.
你好, 古蒂・高德威克.
Good day, Goody Gotwick.
我Я诉@些o丁梅斯黛牧
I brought these for Reverend Dimmesdale.
牧可能正在工作，太太
The Reverend be occupied with his work, Missus.
把放桌上，我保C他能拿到
Leave them books on the table and I'll be sure he gets them.
您好，牧
Good morrow, Reverend.
您好，白m因太太
Good morrow, Mistress Prynne.
知道您很想x一些新
Knowing you hunger for new reading,
我奈艺煞房Y拿了一些o你
I brought you some books.
您太客饬
How courteous of you.
吧
Please.
我很抱歉安息日那天我f了很冒昧的
I must apologize for my forthrightness on Sabbath last.
我男〉酱樽约旱男闹笨诳彀ち瞬簧俚呢R
I've earned a few reprimands for speaking too bluntly.
我，我也道歉
I owe an apology, too.
我不明白我槭颤N如此反感那N
I can't understand why I took such offence
率真的u
to such a simple comment.
我想知道
But I have wondered
您怎N能
how you were able
ξ业谋拘
to see so deeply
看得如此深刻
into my nature.
也S我是女巫
Perhaps I'm a witch.
我不能再您M心了
I must be keeping you from your chores.
xx您的，白m因太太
Thank you for the books.
再
Good day.
我很抱歉，我手上全是墨水
I'm sorry. My hands are covered in ink.
我一直
I've been
整天都在忙活著翻g的事
hovered over my translations all day.
翻g？
Translations?
是的，我一直打算
Aye. I'm attempting to
把}翻g成本地的印第安Z言
translate the Bible into the local Indian language,
阿耳昆Z
Algonquin.
雄心勃勃的
What an ambitious undertaking.
可是我f印第安人不}的指引
But I'm told the Indians don't want to be guided by our Bible.
所以跟他的不可避免
That war with them is inevitable.
有人是@酉耄但是他e了
Some think that way, but they're wrong.
因橛〉诎踩瞬惶容易被征服，
The Indians, born from a certain liberty,
他天生地桀不Z
take not easily to bridle and bit.
男人本色
No man should.
嗯……
Well...
怎N？
What?
怎N了？
你往上T了墨水
You keep putting ink on your face.
哦
Oh, I do.
知道了
There you are.
希望你能喜g那些
I do hope you enjoy the books.
xx
Thank you.
再
Good day.
米杜芭？
Mituba?
那只是浴盆 不是撒旦的玩偶
'Tis only a bathing tub, not a toy of Satan.
白m因太太?
Mistress Prynne?
丁梅斯黛牧
Reverend Dimmesdale!
- 你了我一跳 - Σ黄穑我不是故意的
- You frightened me. - I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
不，是很大的@喜
It's a wonderful surprise.
- @赫嫫亮 - 是的，也很人
- It's beautiful. - Yes, and frightening.
伊甸@不^如此
Just as Eden must have been.
美妙o比
So untouched.
是不是可以大地l誓f
Does it not cry out with it's promise,
@Y的一切可以重新_始
that everything can begin anew?
我把您的砹
I brought back your books.
你不可能在四天的rg全看完了
You couldn't have read them all in four days.
哦不，看完了，大多都看了杀
Oh no, I did. I read most of them twice.
xx你
Thank you.
不客
You're welcome.
再
Farewell.
海z特...
Hester...
我不是你看到的那
I'm not the man I seem.
我一直都住在@Y，我的目嗣鞔_
I've lived here all my life, my purpose clear.
可F在我意拿我的生命，我的位，我的`魂冒U
But now I'd risk everything, my life, my ministry, my soul
只榕c您追昼
just to spend a few moments alone with you.
上帝椭我，海z特.
God help me, Hester.
我勰
I love thee.
上帝椭我，我也勰
God help me. I love thee too.
哦，我迷失方向了幔
Oh God. Have we lost our way?
不
No!
我粢你向我A吐心
I dreamed of thee speaking thy heart.
我一直在祈求一直在渴望
I have prayed for it even as I have dreaded it.
到你之前我究竟是生是死
Was I alive before I laid eyes on thee?
我怎Nk
What shall we do?
我不知道
I know not.
fc什N我停止
Say something to end it,
我o能榱
for I have not the power.
我也是
Nor I.
不，
Nay!
我因此被g死
We could be hanged for this.
我置你於危U之中
I've put you in too much danger,
我一定要停止K且走_，再也不能跟你f了
and I must end it by walking away and never speaking with you again.
走吧
Go then.
信守你的Z言
Do as you promised.
整漫L的夏天，白m因太太和丁梅斯黛牧
Throughout the long summer, Mistress Prynne and the Reverend
想方O法避免面
avoided each other at all costs.
白m因太太缀醪绘子上恚丁梅斯黛牧躲M了荒野
Mistress Prynne rarely went to town and the Reverend escaped to the wilds
只有印第安人
with the Indians
和忠的s翰尼c之榘
and faithful Johnny Sassamon for company.
殖民地照常ek
And the colony organized
xe日L年c祝
it's annual election day as usual.
]人知道他之中
No one the wiser that there existed among them
有深w心正在c劭
two hearts struggling against a love
而@N郏sc日俱增
that grew stronger with each passing day.
他在f什N
Johnny Sassamon says they've attacked the "Intrepid".
阿瑟?
What's he saying,
他f塔m泰人
Arthur?
攻袅艘凰矣船，o畏
The Tarrantines
船上的人都被⒘
attacked an English ship, the Intrepid.
"白m因".
All were massacred.
"_堋ぐ滋m因t生".
"Prynne".
白m因太太.
"Doctor Roger Prynne".
我是作槟愕哪磉@旱
Mistress Prynne.
M
I'm here as your minister.
有一支印第安人
Come in.
他攻袅宋的船
There was an attack,
他f
an Indian attack on one of our ships.
船上的人都被⒘
They say that,
我非常z憾
all aboard were massacred.
o您磉@噩耗
I regret to be...
我走了，您哀吧
the one to bring you this sad news.
你肯定]有一存者幔
I'll leave you to your mourning.
他f海浪把企w都_走了
Are you certain none survived?
上帝恕我
They say that the tide washed away the bodies.
楂@得自由我祈求了很久
God forgive me!
他的死不是你造成的，海z特
I've prayed so long to be set free.
上帝……
You did not cause his death, Hester.
ё吡四阏煞
God...
是的，@是上帝ξ业幕幔
took your husband.
上帝是@幼龅幔
But was it an answer to my prayers?
也S吧
Does He work like that?
如果在它看]有其它k法
Perhaps.
我在一起
If in His eyes there was no other way
我得看看法律怎Nf
we could be together.
服势诙嗑茫要等多Lrg
I must know what the law is.
一月？六月？怎N？
The mourning, how long must one wait?
但是@o法C明他已^λ劳
1 month? Six months? What?
我就必要等七年之後才能公T於世
Where there is no absolute proof of death,
七年?
7 years must pass before we're free to be seen in public.
是的
7 years?
祝R你，特坎姆
Yes...
我一直是橙
Greetings, Metacomet.
但是F在我必FY起
We have been
打糌婪的英人
enemies.
不然他把我s下海
But now Tarrantine
所以我o你砹诉@Y物
and Wampanoag must unite
一英t生
to fight
我FY起
the greedy English.
你f怎N
before theypush us into
印第安人δ忍幔？
the sea.
我鹤铀泪
Were the Indians cruel to you, Mary?
他ξ艺娴耐好的
After my little one died,
f句心Y
they treated me fair and square.
xx
If truth be told,
我回磲崮ξ业B度才算是忍
cruel is how you folks have treated me since I come home.
]有哪件事不是逼著我值
Thank you.
只要一想想被野人子
I didn't do nothing that wasn't forced on me!
我就X得f心
The thought of being taken by a savage
野人是在R背上做那件事的
makes me sick to my stomach.
一跑一做
Well, they do it on the backs of their horses,
海z特，你]事吧
ridin' across the land.
Γ我]事，我只是累了
Hester, you all right?
f得
Yes, I'm just tired.
你管他叫野人
Mary's right.
我可以ff你亡夫做^的好事
You call them savages.
不^那是你Y婚前的事了
I could tell you a thing or two
你@D
about your husband before he tied the knot with you.
哈洛德^不跟妓女有什N瓜葛
Stupid slut!
你以]有？
Harold would never had nothing to do with no whore!
我甚至看^一M嘴牧}的牧
You think not?
跟印第安女人鬼混
I've even seen one of your windy ministers
榱烁加快活他_下|著}
pokin' an Injun girl,
怪不得他都f}能人NA
standin' on a bible so he could roger her better.
我拒^c嘲笑}的人呆在同一房gY
They always said the Scriptures should uplift you!
好的
I refuse to be with those who would mock the Holy Book!
短rg人不回砹
Well,
λ碚f是解
she'll not be coming back soon.
可是我教友派J槁}本身K不是宗教
Good riddance to her!
只不^是x式和v史而已
We Quakers believe that the Scriptures be not religion,
我同意
but only the ceremony and history of it.
那些戒律不^是凡夫俗子的{空想像
I agree.
我的的精神才是真正碜蕴焯玫穆音
For are not the laws of men but the imagination of mortals,
海z特
and the inner spirit the true voice of Heaven?
但你不是在暗示
Hester,
你可以直接通神吧
I pray you're not sayin' you talk directly
你不知道
to the Deity?
只有那些拿高俸的}巨人才能通神
Don't you know that
小心c，孩子
only paid Bible-thumpers can do that?
不然他像我那诱你
Have a care, child,
我知道有些人J
or they'll talking of you the way they talk of me!
@诱f是大不敬
I know some consider it blasphemous to say this,
可男r候起
but I do talk to God.
我就和上帝υ，上帝也回我
I have since I was a small child.
_堋ぐ滋m因太太
And He answers me.
受R塞T塞海持趁竦乜督之命
Mistress Roger Prynne...
明天上午八c
by order of the Governor of Masachusetts Bay Colony,
你要接受L者和谭ü俚判
you are ordered to appear before the magistrates
不得有`
at eight tomorrow morn!
白m因太太,
Don't be tardy!
@些先生指控你x叛道
Mistress Prynne,
你是否跟其他人f^ 戒律只是凡人的想像
these gentlemen have laid a charge ofheresy againstyou.
他Q之楫端者的聚
Tell me how it is the laws ofmen are the imagination ofmortals?
不止是c野人的通
It is the meetings thatyou call heresy.
落的女人好人大肆辱R
Lascivious talk offornication with savages.
]有一有Y格的男人加以指
Fallen women who tell lies about good citizens.
@些女人就信口胡言，f出大不敬的
This is what comes when there is no qualified man present
先生，如果女人的是信口胡言
to guide these women in their untutored chatterings.
那槭颤N}告]我，女人做女人的教呢
If the discourse of women is untutored chattering,
海z特，您停止@N聚
why does the Bible teach that women shall be the teachers of women?
不，先生 我不停止聚
Hester, we ask that you cease these meetings.
阿瑟，加入我
No, sirs. I'll not stop the meetings.
我~回硐壬
Arthur. Please join us.
我站在原地你感x我的
I've been fishing, sir..
- 好吧，坐下 - 我想疽晃蛔C人
You may thank me to remain where I am.
很重要幔
- Please be seated. - Call our first witness.
是的，@非常重要
Is it truly of import?
好吧，髂愕淖C人
Yes, it is of great consequence.
古蒂・高德威克？
Very well, call your witness.
你站起恚古蒂
Goody Gotwick?
你跟我妻子透露我了最人心的一件事情
Stand up, Goody.
告V我，一女人在早晨I吐
You revealed to my wife something very disturbing.
意味著什N
Tell me, what does it mean when a woman
在早晨，而且不只是在一地方I吐
vomits in the morning hours?
我只她吐^一次
And vomits more than once in the morning hours?
是幔有
I only saw her the one time.
古蒂・姆提看她在市鐾逻^
Yes. And?
你是否言辛耍太太
Goody Mortimer saw her get sick in the market.
回答}，女人
Are you with child?
你肚子Y是不是阎野N
Answer your betters, woman!
是的
Do you carry a bastard child in yur womb?
孩子的父H是l？
Yes.
如果f出躲在你裙子後面的男人你就o罪
Who is the father?
我要g死那私通者
You are innocent next to the one who would hide behind your skirts.
我不f出他的名字，先生
We would hang that fornicator!
我告V你他的名字
I'll not reveal the name, sir.
他叫撒旦
I will tell you his name!
他叫j
His name is Lucifer!
他叫十翰簧
His name is Legion!
先生
His name is lust!
你想怎N了
Gentlemen,
你很清楚]有法律禁止言
What do you hope to accomplish?
可有法律禁止通
You know there is no law against pregnancy.
只有她丈夫活著那才能叫通
But there is against adultery.
你是不是蚜艘胺N
It would only adultery if her husband were found to be alive.
我要g死那通Ψ
The meetings will stop!
以通ψ锇阉P起砟蔷也就能阻止
Governor,
督大人
if you knew the name of this man, would you punish Hester Prynne?
如果你知道那男人，你把海z特・白m因P起
Has she confessed the name to you?
她跟你坦白^
I've confessed nothing!
我跟他什N都]f^
- Tell us the truth, Arthur. - He knows nothing of my affairs.
- 真相是什N， 阿瑟. - 他ξ业乃绞赂本不t解
He speaks as my pastor to spare me your harsh hand.
- f出真相，阿瑟 - 作槲业哪，他⒕任异赌的魔掌
But I fear not your punishments!
可我不怕你的土P
I love and honor the man who has fathered this child!
我敬重也很圻@孩子的父H
And say what you will, he is my true husband for life,
S你怎Nf 他⑹俏医裆真正的丈夫
and I shall furnish no information which might cause him harm.
而我根本不可能 f出任何o他害的
Very well, you leave me no choice.
那好吧，太太，你我eox
You're under arrest.
你被捕了
Is this your new Jerusalem?
你槭颤N要抓她
Let me have a moment alone with the woman.
我跟@女人为呆一
- I can draw the name from her. - You shall have your chance.
- 我肯定能她f出他的名字 - 很好，阿瑟，你有@C，我保C
Gentlemen.
先生
I've considered all the arguments
我考]^所有意之後
and decided Arthur is allowed to speak to Mistress Prynne alone.
我Q定必允S阿瑟 为跟白m因太太
Hester Prynne,
海z特・白m因
place your hand on the Good Book.
把你的手放在}上
Let us pray.
我\告
Why did you not tell me?
你槭颤N不告V我
I was afraid.
我害怕
I thought if I worked hard, I would miscarry.
我以檗彰只罹湍芰鳟a
I must go to Bellingham with the truth.
我必f出真相
No, you must not!
不，不能f
You are a saint to these people! They'll hang you for betraying them!
λ碚f你是}徒 他因楸撑讯g死你
I prefer to hang, than allow you to suffer for me.
那就g死我吧 也比你代我受^要好
They've no case against me!
可他]有P我的理由
- When they tire, they'll release me. - I know Stonehall.
- 等他吵累了就把我放出去的 - 我t解斯D赫
You've challenged him,
你在挑鹚
and he'll not release you
他不放^你
until you are humbled and have recanted your sins.
除非你得恭K承J自己有罪
Do you believe we've sinned?
你J槲有罪幔
I know not.
我知道]有
What happen between us had a consecration. Have you forgotten?
我相郾旧砭褪且环NNA 我感X如此美妙y道你忘了
I've not forgotten!
我]有忘
Arthur, I know you want to speak out.
阿瑟，我知道你想f出
Your nature cries out for it.
你人本性Q定你想f出真相
But you risk your own ruin and deny me
可你那У糇约
my right to stand up to this hypocrisy.
也Z我反抗@N紊频嗬
Soldier!
士兵
If I need you to speak,
如果我想跟你f
I'll tie this handkerchief from the window.
我把手M在@窗羯
I love thee woman,
我勰悖海z特
but your strength frightens me.
可你的勇庾我害怕
I'll do what you ask.
我照你f的做
Amen.
阿T
God be with you.
上帝c你同在
I'm sure he already is.
我相信他已同在了
Gentlemen,
先生
Mistress Prynne has been there more than 5 months
白m因太太在@YP了五月
without any legal justification.
而]有受到任何合法的判，槭颤N？
Even in Plymouth they regard this as barbaric!
甚至B落後的普利毛斯人都指 @Υ她是野U行
I'd like to free her. At home, I have no peace on this.
我也很想把她放，阿瑟 @件事我在家Y不得安生
But the people see us go to her week after week, caps in hand,
F在是人看著我 一星期接一星期找她
only to be turned away.
s只能o功而返
The woman is unrepentant!
@女人不J罪，不曰
She's fortunate we haven't beaten her publicly!
]有鞭打她已算是她幸\了
I'm surprised at you Reverend. You came here a man of reason.
我很奇怪，奇夫牧. 你r是很理智的
I came here expecting some semblance of order.
我磉@海先生 是要找到一N有效的秩序
Instead I find a den of fractiousness!
可我找到的s是蔚某惭
Sir, if you do not stem this dissent,
先生，如果你不阻止@N端
my wife and I will return to England.
我和我妻子Q定返回英
And take our parishioners!
而且ё咚有的教^居民
If only she would give us
她只要表示
a small sign of contrition.
一cc悔悟就可以了
Ifit had been up to him, my father,
如果我父H能做Q定
he would have ended it and revealed the truth ofmy origins.
他把把我的身世透露出 Kt解@件事
But bound by my mother's wish, he could not.
- _ - 可是榱宋夷赣H的意，他不能@幼
He went every day to see her and was refused.
- 不S探 - 直可褐O
His eye everon that window forhersign that it was time
他每天都去看，每天都被拒^
to come forward with the truth.
每他在窗羯峡吹侥擞r
Had there been flashes ofPrynne's unstable nature before
他都X得他站出恚f出真相
in England?
白m因反覆o常的本性
No one knows.
在英可曾出F^
But now, free from Puritan society,
]有人知道
he was increasingly seized by spirits so powerful
F在他m然x_了清教徒社
they were terrifying even to the Indians.
可他是受困於日u增多的清戒律中
He has a ghost in him.
@些戒律大得B印第安人都X得可怕
He'll bring us bad luck.
他的身wY一定有幽`
Send him home.
他o我矶蜻\
Forgive me, Lord,
送他回家吧
forI have turned from my Heavenly Father.
恕我，上帝
Forgive me.
我已背x了你，我的}父
Lord, bring me back to thy bosom.
恕我
God's teeth, child! How could they leave you thus?
我重回你的驯
I'm so glad you're here!
可z的孩子，他怎N能不管你
6 months and not one visitor.
我很高d你在@
Some of us came, my dear, but we were turned away.
六月都]有人砜次
Your slave came every day. How quick are the pains?
我想恚H鄣 可他不M
- They're not stopping. - Here.
你的奴`每天都 F在，疼得害幔
Take a sip of this.
- ]停^ - 戆
I wager you won't refuse my cider this time.
喝一口@
Rvd. Dimmesdale tried always to get you freed.
我告V你，@次e拒^我的O果酒
- Another? - Yes.
丁梅斯黛牧想M了方法想把你弄出去
All right, breathe deep. Breathe deep.
- 要幔 - 是的
Hold on to me! Good girl!
哦，H鄣模戆桑深呼吸 深呼吸
Easy, easy.
我在@海抓o我，很好，姑娘
Let me see.
放，放
All's well. All's well. It's close.
我看看，我看看
It's very close. Come, my dear. It's time.
好的好的，一切都好
Up you sit.
快了，我H鄣模是r候了
Good girl. There.
你坐起
Move down a little. Good.
Γ好姑娘
This child is ready to be born.
下硪稽c
We've work to do!
@孩子生得真是r候
There.
我可有事做了
How could they keep me here so long?
好的
Well, I'll say this,
我]想到他P我@N久
you must have a will of iron.
我f
When you take on the men, it leads to death.
你一定有F般的意志
All right, my dear. Chin down and bear down hard!
要是Q了男人 他早就死了
More and harder!
好的，H鄣模F在
Harder! Good!
深呼吸，深呼吸
Good girl. That's it.
再使牛再
Easy.
好，好，
放
Good. Easy.
Are you sure God's not punishing me?
好，好，放
To be sure he's punishing you.
上帝是在土P我
He be giving you a child!.
f真的，土P你
Now. Gently.
是要o你孩子
Now the head is coming.
用牛再
The head is through.
哦，^出砹
Just a little more. Easy.
看了，看了
Easy. Easy.
慢c，肩膀出砹
She'd here!
放，放
Oh, thank you, God!
是丫^
Yes!
上帝，xx你
Little Pearl. Yes!
是的
Yes!
小，是的
Harriet, she's here!
是的
She's here.
我的，她在@
Sit there, Mistress.
她在@
Proceed, Reverend.
坐下吧，太太
I'll have them fetch fresh clothes for you and the babe.
_始吧，牧.
I bring good news.
我他去o你和孩子拿乾Q的衣服
I've prevailed upon the Governor.
我砹撕孟息
You are to be freed.
我已f服了督
But by law...
⒛汜放
you'll be brought to the scaffold
不^根法律
for reprimand.
你被送到g刑架
Hester.
接受
Whatever is said,
海z特
please,
不管他f什N
be as contrite as your conscience permits.
求你
If not for my sake, for the babe's.
假b\心悔恨
I beg you, don't anger them further!
就算不槲遥也要榱撕⒆
I've come to baptize the babe.
求你不要再激怒他 有r
I've died not seeing you.
我斫o@孩子做洗Y
I came every day.
我快著急死了
I baptize this child,
我每天都
Pearl.
我o@孩子做洗Y
珠
In the name of the Father,
珠海
and the son,
以}父
and the Holy Ghost.
}子
May the Lord bless thee,
}`的名x
and care for thee,
上帝祝福你
and watch over thee.
P勰
Amen.
保佑你
Freeing this woman
阿T
is an invitation to every wife
放@女人
to defy her husband.
就等於Z恿每一妻子
Every child it's parent!
背叛她的丈夫
No, she should be released.
每一孩子背叛他的父母
What?
不，把她放
You don't put her in prison,
什N？
you put the prison in her.
不要把她PMOz
So each time someone sees her,
而要把Oz建在她的心Y
her sin will be marked into her soul afresh.
@用看未蠹铱此的r候
Cunningly contrived, my dear.
她的`魂⒅匦麓蛏献旱睦佑
Make way in the King's name.
真是好主意，H鄣
A blessing on the righteous Colony of Massachusetts,
以王的名x步
where iniquity is dragged into the sunlight!
我祝福R塞T塞海岸殖民地Y
Know ye
不公正的行楸槐┞对陉光下
that Mistress Roger Prynne
今天在龅娜硕贾道
has been ordered
_堋ぐ滋m因太太
to bear punishment for fornication and adultery.
一直因槠浔撑押屯π
If it be determined later
而受土P
that her husband be still alive,
如果以後能_定
she may face a most severe penalty,
她的丈夫活著
which is to be hanged by the neck until dead.
那她⑹艿礁加的土P
Pray, silence, for his Excellency,
也就是接受g刑至死
the Governor.
上帝保佑
Hester Prynne,
尊敬的督w下署
though you show no modesty in you apparel,
海z特・白m因,
yet you have a chance, still, to repent your sins.
m然你]有表F出真\
Yes, Hester, repent!
不^你仍然有C悔^
Child, don't you believe you have sinned?
悔^吧，海z特
I believe I have sinned in your eyes,
孩子，你是否相信你犯了罪
but who is to know if God shares your views?
我相信你J槲矣凶
Woman,
可l知道上帝是不是J同你
transgress not the limits of Heaven's mercy!
D人
Reverend Dimmesdale, you are her pastor.
你不要超越上天仁慈的界限
Speak to her for all our sakes!
丁梅斯黛牧 你是她的牧
Soften her, her hardness her obstinacy!
跟她
Listen to the Reverend!
榱宋大家，_她 e她冥B不化
Speak to the woman, my brother.
跟她，牧
Exalt her to confess the truth!
跟她吧，我的兄弟
Hester Prynne,
袼f出真相
you hear what these good men say,
海z特・白m因,
and see the accountablity under which I labor.
@些好人的了
For your soul's peace,
你可以看出我承了多大的任
I charge thee
榱四沆`魂的安
speak out the name
我令你
of your fellow sinner.
f出另一
Be not silent
有罪者的名字
for some mistaken pity or tenderness for him.
你不要因
For believe me, if he could
e`的同情和P鄱保持沉默了
step down and stand beside you on your pedestal of shame,
相信我，如果那人站出
it would be better than to
c你K肩站在@Y受辱
carry a guilty heart through life.
要好^他
What can your silence do for him,
е一w愧疚之心悔恨K生
except to tempt him?
你的沉默能樗做什N
And compel him
你是想T惑他
to add hypocrisy to sin?
是想迫他
Speak.
背另一罪名
She will not speak.
f吧
In the name of the Lord, name him!
她不肯f
Name him!
以上帝的名x，g死他
- His name! - What is his name?
g死他
Who might he be?
- 快f吧 - 他是l
Very well.
那男人是l
Beadle!
那好吧
Mistress, if you do not speak out
淌
his name, wear upon your bodice
太太，如果你不f出他的名字
this symbol of your sinful fornication.
你必在胸前焐
Heed not this
@罪旱耐Φ擞
final warning,
@是最後一次
and you will be a pariah,
警告
cut off, shunned and reviled by every man,
你今天起你⒊橐v民
woman and child in this town!
被@子上的每男人 女人，和孩子
Why do you wait? Put it on!
逐，隔x和斥
It is not a badge of my shame, but your own!
你等什N 焐习
What do you want?
它代表的不是我的u辱而是你的
Have I changed so much, my beloved,
你想质颤N
that you would slay me as I resurrect myself from the dead?
y道我了很多幔H鄣
Roger?
甚至在我死而蜕之後你要⑺牢
Hester.
_埽
Was I ever unkind to you?
海z特.
Did I not love thee?
y道我δ悴蚝幔
Did I not see thee above all womanhood?
y道我不勰幔
Are you not bound to me by sacred oath?
y道我不是把你置於所有女人之上？
Or has this new land turned thee into a heathen?
神}的誓言]有把你交o我？
Lay our bed will thou, wife.
是@K新土地把你成了教徒？
Pray for thy sins, Hester Prynne.
躺到我的床上，我的妻子
Beg the Lord to forgive thy corruption.
槟愕淖锒\告吧，海z特・白m因.
Pray and I'll wash thee as white as snow.
祈求上帝恕你的不忠
White as snow, my love.
祈\，我把你洗得白如雪
White as snow.
是的H鄣模白如雪
白如雪
Arthur?
Hester?
阿瑟?
Thank God you're here!
海z特?
- Why are you taking this risk? - I had to warn you.
感x上帝你在@
My husband is alive.
- 槭颤N要冒@U - 我o你缶
Dear God!
我丈夫，_埽他活著
Alive?
啊，H鄣纳系
Now we'll hang for certain.
他活著？
Why would he show up at this moment if he wasn't God's dark messenger,
我肯定被g死
sent to punish us.
他槭颤N在此刻F身 y道他是上帝派
Arthur, you must leave without us.
土P我的黑暗使者
I cannot bear to see you trapped here,
阿瑟，你必x_@
under his watchful eye forever.
我不忍心看到你生活在他
Hester, I must stay and watch over you and Pearl.
警惕的目光之下
No. You don't know him.
海z特，我不能x_ 我必留下碚湛茨愫椭
He'll wait for us to betray each other
不，你不t解他
with the slightest glance or the merest gesture.
他等我出uΨ
Please. You must go!
哪怕是一p柔的眼神或是微的手
This God's punishment,
求你了，你必走
because we tried to run from His Will.
@是上帝的土P
I will not say farewell, Hester.
因槲曾想[他的意旨
Pray God watch over you.
我不x_你的，海z特.
And so will I.
但上帝c你同在
Kiss Pearl for me each night.
我也c你同在
'Tis easy to see the mother's part in her.
每晚替我H吻珠
Is it beyond research, I wonder,
容易看出一部分像
to analyze her nature, and from it's make and mold,
不知道是不是超越了哲人的研究
give a shrewd guess as to the father?
倪@孩子的性格和外貌砜
What are your expectations?
大概猜得出她的父H是l
I do not expect your heart to return to you quickly.
你有什N打算，先生
But I hope one day you will draw me again
哦，H鄣 我不指望你能很快回心D意
into your heart.
但我希望有一天 你重新把我
Love has forced me to open my heart to another.
放M你的心Y
Watch your tongue, woman!
圩我把心向另一人敞_
'Tis this phantom lover who puts these words into your mouth1
eyf，太太
Where is he?
那教你f@些的影子情人
Is his kiss
他在哪海
still wet on your lips, on your breast?
他嘴角的
- I demand to know! - If I spent 6 months in a cold jail,
仍然停留在你的嘴唇 或者是你的胸前
and did not tell these iron men,
- 我想知道 - 我坐了六月冰冷的牢房
what makes you think I'll tell you now?
也]有告V那些人
These trials have made me strong!
你{什NJ槲跟你f
And I am not the child you married!
@些判我更了，先生
Why not announce yourself openly and cast me off at once.
我不再是你娶的那小姑娘了
No, no.
你槭颤N不R上公_宣寻盐倚莸
I seek no vengeance against you.
不，不
But the man lives who wronged us both.
我不想δ停孩子
He bears no letter of infamy
可拆散我的人活著
wrought into his garment.
他的外衣上]有一
But I shall read it on his heart.
揭露他h行的字
Breathe one word to him of my true identity,
可我能蚩吹剿心上的字
and you will both hang.
敢把我的真身份透露o他一字
If you try to escape,
你就被g死
you will be easily found.
如果你愚蠢地想逃走
Easily!
那你很快就被lF的
From the savages
很好
I have learned patience,
囊靶U人那Y
Hester Prynne.
我W了耐心
Goody Gotwick, thank you.
海z特・白m因.
Reverend, allow me to introduce our newest boarder,
古蒂・高德威克，xx
Doctor Chilling...
丁梅斯黛牧牧 允S我斫榻B一位新房客
- Chillingworth. - Chillingworth.
奇林
Good day, man.
- 奇林・沃斯 - 奇林・沃斯
Good day, sir.
你好，牧
What brings you to our colony, sir?
你好，先生.
I'm a physician, sir. I would cleanse the ills
槭颤N要砦的殖民地，先生
of the community.
我是t生，先生 我可以榇蠹
Have I said something strange?
祛除疾病
No.
我f的有什N不幔
I'm amazed.
不
We have prayed for a skilled physician.
只是我很好奇
I see you are translating the Bible into Algonquin.
我一直祈求一位tg高明的t生
A most difficult tongue to master.
我看你正把}g成阿昆Z
If I can be of help, Reverend.
那是最y懂的一NZ言
I am fluent in Algonquin.
我希望能蜕厦Γ丁梅斯黛牧
- Fluent? - Yes.
我的阿昆Z很流利
I was a prisoner of the Tarrantine.
- 流利？ - 是的
When I spoke improperly, I was whipped.
哦，是的，我做^塔m泰人的俘
I learned quite rapidly.
只要我f的不Γ他就打我
How were you captured?
所以我W得突w猛M
I was working my farm in Virginia. They came,
你是怎N被抓住的
killed my wife, Eleanor, God rest her soul,
我在弗吉尼r龉ぷ鞯r候 他砹
and our infant son,
⒘宋业钠拮廴RZ 她的`魂安息
and sold me into captivity.
和我尚未L大的鹤
It's a wonder you're not consumed
然後把我作榉u掉
with bitterness and despair.
很奇怪你K]有^多的
No, no. In truth, I am indebted to the Indians.
痛苦和失望
Some say they are savages, but true savagery,
不，不，f，先生 我欠印弟安人的
I find resides elsewhere.
有人f他是野U人 可我lF真正的野U人
Mistress Roger Prynne.
s在e的地方
Mistress Prynne.
_堋ぐ滋m因太太
And what is your duty, boy?
白m因太太.
Follow you around, Mistress.
，孩子
Well, at least they'll make a path for me.
你的是什N，孩子
Whore!
跟著你去每一公共鏊，太太
God will punish you, sinner!
很好，至少他o我路
Jezebel!
L回去，v人
You're not welcome here!
上帝土P你的，罪人
Be gone, Hester Prynne!
v人
Soap, please. Three pieces.
你在@翰皇g迎
Although he wore no outward symbol ofhis shame,
走吧，海z特・白m因!
my father wore his own scarlet letteron the bosom ofhis soul.
我要I肥皂，o我三K
The pain of their separation must have affected us all.
m然我父H身上]熘t字
I was a troublesome child.
可他自己的t字就印在他的`魂上
My father ached formy mother,
分x的痛苦影了大家.
and filled his loneliness in the wilds with Johnny.
我是一非常yp的孩子
They struggled
榻庀嗨贾苦
to keep alive their  dream
父Hеs翰尼去野外以求[孤
of building a bridge between English and Indian.
他想在英人和印第安人之g
Johnny,
架起一座
why are they so close to town?
K且努力So著@粝
They say our people have fallen asleep.
s翰尼
So they must remain awake for all of us.
他x子槭颤N@N近
I'm worried.
他f，我的人都睡了
Is war coming?
所以他必保持清醒
The great experiment is not working, is it?
我很心
Yes, he's right.
有幔阿瑟
If there's war, what is to stop our praying Indians
ゴ蟮粝肫缌耍是幔
from rising up
他f的
and slitting our throats as we sleep?
如果真的有 如何阻止那些皈依的印第安人叛
Faith, Thomas. Faith.
趁著我睡X的r候
I know what will stop them.
割辔的喉
Arthur's friendship with Johnny Sassamon.
信念，托R斯，信念
Johnny would never betray Arthur.
我知道什N能阻止他
He worships him.
阿瑟cs翰尼的友x
As Peter worshipped
s翰尼^不背叛阿瑟
Jesus.
他崇拜阿瑟
Gentlemen. Doctor.
就像彼特崇拜
If there's a true war,
耶d
God help us all.
先生，t生
for neither we nor the savaged will survive it.
如果真的有
I see the governor appreciates the signs less than yee,
就求上帝吧
his Godly advisors.
我和野U人都活不了
It is not always easy.
我看督徵兆的判嗔Ρ炔簧纤
Strangely, the same thing happened in Virginia.
他的虔\的.
Before the attack,
不事事如意
there were signs that went unheeded.
很奇怪，弗吉尼也是如此
What manner of signs?
在他攻糁前
The bad winter. The crop failures.
根本]有任何徵兆
Far too many Quakers and foreigners in the town.
什N拥尼缯祝
Some minor elements
寒冷的冬天，Z食欠收
of witchcraft, etc.
子Y有^多的信徒和外砣
Exactly!
一些小小的不安分子
Our first sign was that
T如此
of Hester Prynne and her women's meetings.
f的Γf的
Then the severe winter.
我的第一徵兆是
The failed crops.
海z特・白m因和她的那些聚
You see, sir,
然後又是篮的冬天
my colleague has feared from the start,
Z食欠收
that in the matter of Mistress Prynne,
您看，先生
witchcraft was involved.
我的同事囊婚_始
Then why in all this time have you not taken measures
就心白m因太太的事
to cleanse your colony?
跟巫g有PS
What measures do you speak of?
槭颤N一直以砟]有袢∵m的措施
Did you examine the women present at those meetings?
清殖民地？
Have you queried the midwife,
您的意思是？
or inspected the child for the witch's marks?
你查^那些⒓泳的女人幔
I shall fear no evil.
有]有^接生的人
I prepare us a table in the presence of thine enemy.
或者z查^那孩子有]有女巫的擞
My cup
m然我要穿越死亡影之地
runneth over.
可我不怕邪
Surely goodness
因橛心存在，有您嗾鹊闹敢，有您o我安慰
and mercy shall follow me.
您我的橙伺c我坐在同一桌前
I will dwell in the house of the Lord.
您槲沂T油之Y
The babe's clean,
您oM的仁慈和zc我同行
at present.
而我⒂肋h做您的W人
Hester,
孩子很乾Q
we shall leave your child with you for the present,
到目前橹
but you must assure us it will be raised a Christian.
海z特太太,
Yes, yes.
我把孩子r留o你
Yes.
可你要保C她成榛督信徒
I've been your friend today.
是的，是的
But it cannot always be so. No.
我的
For inside me I grow more wretched by the day.
今天我是你的朋友，孩子
I yearn so much for thee.
但是不可能天天如此，不
I fear I might destroy
因槲倚闹械某鸷蓿c日俱增
her whole world to win her back.
我是那N地渴望你
Tell old Harriet what's troubling you.
我怕我因槟
I never imagined
把整世界У
how cruel and cunning their punishment could be.
告V老哈里森 什N事你心
Stonehall y Cheever stop to preach at me in the street.
我真]有想到
The people pointing and shouting.
他的土P@忍和狡p
Even the children.
斯D赫和奇夫在大街上槲仪描打鼓
And that horrible drummer boy following me everywhere.
上的人ξ抑更c，漫R
Perhaps it was all for naught.
甚至有孩子
I wonder if to be a woman is worthwhile at all.
那可旱男」氖指著我到走
Even for the happiest of women.
也S@也是徒诘
Courage, child.
我作榕人不能^快返囊簧
Take heart. At least you've known what it is to love.
活著有什N意思
But what if I've repaid it by destroying him?
勇敢c，孩子
What if
至少你知道了什N是
everything I believed so strongly was a lie?
y道鄣拇r是要我У羲
Vain and
y道
selfish.
我一直孕诺囊磺卸际翘假的
Prynne's cruelpunishments
愚蠢
were succeeding.
而自私的
The seasons ran theircourse.
白m因忍的土P
The distance between them was impassable.
在^m著
My mother took the terrible risk ofwriting to my father,
季交替
reminding to keep theirlove and his silence.
而父Hc母H之g的距xo法穿越
The subtle but constant presence ofPrynne
母H冒著O大的危Uo父H信
was a torment
提醒他允厮的矍椋允爻聊
that threatened my father's very soul.
而白m因若有若o
As forPrynne,
接B不嗟爻霈F
his lust forrevenge
折磨著我父H的心`
fed on itself
至於白m因
so that he hungered formore.
他偷j望
Good morrow, Mituba.
_始膨
What a pleasant day for a ride.
他更加本加地
Poor Mituba.
你好，米杜芭
You're renowned for your loyalty to your Mistress, and I see why.
今天真是出T的好天
Was your dry lunch a communication from her lover?
可z的米杜芭
I have the power to arrest you as an accomplice t adultery
你μ太的忠\是出了名的，F在我知道原因了
and bring you before the magistrates for questioning.
你那乾巴巴的午餐是她情人的信
And since you are a slave,
你知道，我有能力把你成通φ叩耐\抓起
they might whip you to death.
把你У焦T面前
Easy. Easy.
不^你是奴`
I only want to help the one we both love.
他可能用鞭子把你打死
To free herself from the grasp of a fiend.
打死，打死
Dear Lord, this is it!
我只想椭我都鄣哪人
He made you strip naked before him!
娜龅┑哪ёο绿映
Totally naked!
哦，我的上帝，蛄
Was there a presence in the room?
他是不是著你的面光
Now think! Think!
全部光
He might have come in one of his many disguises.
r屋Y有人
Did he come as a bird?
好好想想，想想
Oh, God. I feel
也S他是е窝bM淼
the presence of Lucifer!
他是不是成了一bB，
Save yourself before it's too late!
哦，上帝，我感X到了
Gentlemen, please!
魔鬼的存在
Enough!
救救你自己吧 不然就太晚了
先生
Go home, Mituba. You've been a wondrous help.
蛄耍蛄
Commend us to your Mistress.
蛄
Go home.
回去吧，米杜芭 你土撕艽蟮拿
向你的主人FF我
So there is a malignancy
回家吧
to be cut our here.
But what kind of witness will a slave be in court?
@Nf，@河耗
The bird, obviously. is Harriet Hibbons.
需要除
What is it, Pearl?
但是，一奴`上法庭能做什NC
- Forgive me, Hester. - Harriet.
那bB，@然是哈里森・希本斯
Yours was the first place I thought of to hide.
怎N了，珠
What is it?
- 原我，海z特. - 哈里森
They've, they've, they've ah...
我藏在你@是最安全的了
broken into my house. They're looking for me in the woods.
怎N了
I've been named
他，他，
as a witch!
JM了我屋子 F在去淞盅Y找我了
In the name of God!
我被f成是
Halt there!
女巫
Yes, sir!
哦，上帝
What's the meaning of this intrusion?
停下
Stand aside, woman!
是，L官
We know the witch is in here.
你JM我家质颤N，少校
There's no one inside
_，夫人
but me, my child and Mituba.
我知道那女巫在@
So unless you have a warrant, be gone.
@Y]有外人
Reverend Dimmesdale.
只有我，我的孩子和米杜芭
What's happening, major?
要是你]有搜查令，走吧
We've cornered ourselves a witch.
丁梅斯黛牧
Here in Hester Prynne's cottage.
怎N回事，少校
If there's a witch inside the house, major,
我住了一女巫
I'll find her.
在海z特・白m因的屋子Y
Right.
如果@房子Y真的有女巫的，少校
One man at the door.
我找到的
- Soldier! - Sir?
好吧
Pearl's grown tall.
士兵，守住T口
She's an elf.
是的
Willful.
珠洪L高了
Dear God, Hester.
她是淘獍
It's been so long.
很任性
You'r thin.
感x上帝
Are you hiding someone, Hester?
@N久了
Why do you...?
你瘦了
Why are you risking
你藏了什N了幔海z特?
further anger from the elders?
槭颤N
Because she is no witch! She's committed no crime
你槭颤N要冒@U
beyond speaking her mind!
去激怒那些人
If she is innocent,
因樗不是女巫 除了f
I assure you no harm will befall her.
她]有犯^罪
Arthur. After all that has happened,
如果她是o罪的
how can you still trust these iron men?
我向你保C她不受到害
Don't you see what's happening?
阿瑟，l生了@N多事
Last month they brought Sally Short for questioning.
你怎N能相信那些忍的人
They held her for 2 days. Last week it was Mary Rollins.
y道你]看
They just questioned them!
上月他莎・肖特去
What's the crime in that?
他P了她商 上星期是・R林斯
The crime is they had nothing!
海z特，他只是她
Don't you see
@有什N罪
this is some malevolence?
罪行是她什N都]有做
- What has become of you? - God, woman!
你看不出
What are your demands?
@是一憾娟\的一部分
I've given up everything I own sacred!
- 你是怎N了 - 天啊，夫人
I'm in Hell!
你想怎N
In the eye of your husband, who lurks at my side day and night.
榱四阄曳所有神}的|西
In the eye of all who come to me to unburden their soul!
我M了地z
I'm a pollution!
你的丈夫，日夜周旋在我的身
I'm a lie!
而上的居民都碚椅裔放他的心`的
They are the pollution!
我是av的
They are the lie!
我是_子
But you allow them to destroy all that is good in you!
不，他才是av的
What's happened to the man I love?
他才是_子
Does he not still live inside thee?
而你在v容他У裟闵砩厦篮玫|西
Our love, woman, was a folly.
我鄣哪人怎N了
And the voice we heard,
他活在你的身wY
we have been punished for listening to!
我的郏夫人，是荒唐的
What have I become?
我心也是假的
To betray the onlyperson on earth who had shown herkindness.
而我因此受到了土P
What could feel worse than that?
我成什N了
Mituba?
他出u了世界上唯一向她表F出好意的人
Poor, mute Mituba.
有什N比@更糟糕的
When Prynne summoned her,
米杜芭？
she wanted only to undo the harm sh'd caused her Mistress.
可z的米杜芭
Peace in this House!
白m因舅的r候
Peace, I say. Peace!
她只是想消除可能o女主人淼害
You find these proceedings humorous, Mistress?
大家Co
Do you expect me to take them seriously?
Co，我fCo
You're a bunch of grown men
你X得@些程序很好笑幔太太
poking around my private parts looking for witch's marks!
你指望我把它回事
The slave, Mituba...
看著一群成年人揭_我的[私
Peace, I say. Peace!
ふ遗巫的擞不好笑
The witness, the slave Mituba, has been found dead.
那奴`，米杜芭
I told you she was a witch!
Co，Co
- Mistress Hibbons is a witch! - She's a witch!
恐怕我的C人，那奴`，米杜芭 已死了
Witch!
我f^她是女巫
Have you lost all reason?
- 希本斯太太是女巫 - 她是女巫
There's no witchcraft here!
女巫
This is murder!
你都失去理智了
Guards,
@Y]有什N女巫
restrain this woman!
@是\
Satan is not at work here among the women!
警l
But if he's here, perhaps is at work among you men!
制止@女人
Here Satan speaks!
撒旦聿桓街在女人的身上
Governor?
如果他在@海也S就附著在你男人的身上
I have evidence to render.
是撒旦在v
As you know,
督
Mistress Hibbons midwifed Mistress Prynne's
我有C呈f
baby Pearl.
你都知道
Sweet Pearl.
希本斯夫人曾替白m因太太接生
Bastard!
那珠
No!
可鄣闹
Pearl.
sN
I wish you were my girl.
不
Poor fatherless child.
珠海珠海可鄣闹
Would you like to learn a game?
多希望你是我的女
Yes. Now do what I do.
可z的]父H的孩子
If I pinch my nose.
你想玩[
You too. Very good, very good.
好的，照我@幼
Now,
如果我捏我的鼻子
pull up my shirt and show my tummy tum-tum.
你了 很好，很好
Now show me your tummy tum-tum.
F在
Pull up your shirt.
我掀_我的衣服露出我的肚子
Behold the witch's mark!
F在我看看你的肚子
Behold the devil's own child!
掀_你的衣服
The devil's own child! The devil's own child!
@就是女巫的苏I
This woman is innocent!
@就是耗У暮⒆
Innocent? Since you first spoke of this woman,
@就是耗У暮⒆ @孩子被g死
all we've dreames and toiled for in God's name has been threatened!
不
I've heard enough!
把孩子o我
Have you listened?
希本斯是o辜的，不能g死她
Factions! Arguments! Dissent!
o辜？哪愕谝淮槟女人求情
That is the work of Satan!
我以主的名x粝牒^Y的一切就受到了威{
The town was in an uproar.
我已蛄
My fatherrisked one last meeting with my mother,
你了幔
convinced that ifthey were to hang
！q解！分歧！
Harriet, it would not be long
@都是撒旦在做祟
before my motherand I would be seized... and hung.
F在子y成一F
I had to speak out.
我父H冒U最後一次去我母H
I couldn't stop myself.
告V她如果他要g死哈里森
Damn your husband!
那^不了多久
You and Pearl must go in hiding. Tonight.
母H和我也被抓起 然後被g死
I cannot.
我要大喊叫
I cannot run.
我o法控制自己
What are you saying?
{咒你的丈夫吧，海z特
Forgive me.
你和珠罕仨躲起 今晚
Whatever happens,
我不能
promise me you'll look after Pearl. I.
我不能走
God, woman, how much further must you take this?
你在f什N
As far as my strength will take me.
原我
If Harriet is to hang, I must hang with her.
ol生什N
I'll ask the other women to stand with us.
向我保C你永h照珠
They can't hang us all.
上帝，@N痛苦你要承受多久
Hester, are we ever to know a life together?
只要有勇馕揖去接受
I love thee.
如果哈里森被g死 我陪她一起死
I love thee and always will.
我其他女人和我同一
I will always love thee.
他不能把我都g死
Lord God, we stood before thee naked once,
海z特，我永h不能在一起了
and now we stand before thee
我勰
naked again, as a family.
哦上帝啊，我勰悖永h都勰
God! Thou has given me this as a gift,
我也永h勰
and I will not give it up!
上帝啊 我曾毫o保留地站在你面前
Not while I have the strength.
F在作橐患胰
Arthur?
我再次毫o保留地站在你面前
上帝，既然你把@Y物送o了我
Arthur?
我就^不，^不放它
Evening Mistress Prynne. Expecting someone else?
只要我有勇
Ah, no.
阿瑟?
Didn't you call out for Arthur?
The only Arthur I know is... Dimmesdale.
阿瑟?
You misunderstood me, I didn't say...
晚上好，白m因太太. 在等什N人幔
I should have guessed long ago.
哦，不
You naughty girl.
你才不是在叫阿瑟
So you fucked our minister.
我所知，只有一阿瑟 那就是丁梅斯黛
God, I'm about to savour a priceless morsel!
你`解我了 我]有…
Up we go!
我早就猜到
Did he suck your breasts?
你@淘獾墓媚
Did he lick you?
你勾引了我的牧
Where did he lick you?
上帝啊我的}父，我如何品味@or的佳P呢
Show me!
]想到，他δ阕隽耸颤N
How I wanted to put it in you!
他H吻你的胸部？
This is to make you pay for my fantasies.
他舔舐你了幔
While you were torturing me,
他舔舐你什N地方
you were giving it to another.
我看看
Damned witch!
上帝啊，我多希望M入你的身w
Get out!
@就是你我δ惝a生幻想的代r
Do up your britches and get out!
你迷惑我
Bastard! Get out of here!
可你s把身wo了另一人
How I will enjoy watching you and the pastor hang!
死的女巫！
Open up, doctor!
L出去！
There are matters between us we must discus immediately.
穿上你的子L出去！
So, Arthur Dimmesdale.
你@sN！L出去！
At last justice is done!
我很高d看到你和你的牧被g死
？a sido asesinado!
_T，t生
Call out the militia! Call out the guards!
你和我之g的}必R上解Q
It's a sign! The Lord has sent us a sign!
好吧，阿瑟・丁梅斯黛
We have strayed!
@是天意
See how he punishes us!
他被\⒘耍
It's Brewster. Those savages
快去找民兵 快去找警l
have killed him!
@是神E 上帝o了我神E
My son! My son!
肯定是印第安人值,把他P起
Damned heathens!
我偏x了上帝
Lock up the praying Indians,
看他怎N土P我吧
before they murder us in our beds!
是布斯特，那些野U人
Get the praying Indians!
把他o⒘
Praying Indians into the compound!
我的鹤樱∥业鹤樱
We are loyal to you!
死的教徒！
在他把我\⒃诖采现前
By order of the Governor of the Massachusetts Bay Colony,
把那些印第安人P起
you are under arrest for the crime of heresy.
把他P起
Stop this. It was one of us who killed Brewster.
把印第安人PMh笆院子Y
I have proof.
快c
Bastard!
我忠\於你
Johnny, run to Metacomet's place by the river.
白m因太太 受RT海岸殖民地督之命
Tell him to come and save his people. Run, man!
因槟愕姆NN端行 你被逮捕了
Here come the witches!
住手！是我的人⒘瞬剪斯特！
Open the cell.
是我的人，我有C
- Never mind the child. - Pearl!
sN！
- Get in, woman! - Pearl?
s翰尼，特坎姆在河，我看他了
Worry not, Mistress.
告V他快碚救他的人，快去
I'll see she's raised up to fear the Lord.
女巫砹
Open up, murderer!
打_囚\
There is no witchcraft here!
- e管孩子 - 珠!
If we hang these women,
- M去，M去你@女人 - 珠?
then what have we become?
e心，白m因太太
Who are we
- 我把她B大，她敬畏上帝 - 珠
to condemn
如果@是榱俗罡呃益
on God's behalf?
我⒎哪的旨意
I love this woman.
_T，⑷朔
I am
他f的是真的
the father of her child.
大家e那幼
And in God's eyes,
@Y根本]有什N女巫
I am her husband.
g死她
If you must hang someone,
如果我g死@些女人
to appease
那我成了什N
your anger and fear,
我是l
then hang me.
又怎N能代表上帝
Hang him!
谭
Hang him! Hang him!
我深圻@女人
Hang him!
我就是
Bastards!
她孩子的父H
Hester!
在上帝的眼Y
Where's my daughter, Pearl?
我就是她的丈夫
She's in the meeting house!
- g死她 - g死她
You are free, my people. Go back to Metacomet!
F在如果你一定要g死一人
Go back to the forest!
才能消除
Bellingham will do anything to conceal this madness from England.
你的怒和恐
He has sworn to me that he will remove the letter.
那就g死我吧
And make thee a public apology.
g死他！
How close they are, love and hate.
g死他！g死他！
We're no less bound by one than the other.
g死他！
Rest in peace, Roger Prynne.
This letter has served a purpose.
g死他！
Though not the one
sN！
they had intended.
- 珠涸谀 - 她在兵工S
So why would I stay here?
快走
To be accepted by them? To be tamed by them?
海z特
- There is no perfect world. - No, not perfect.
我的女涸谀模
But we came here to make a new one.
她在h室Y
And for Pearl's sake,
你自由了，我的朋友 回特坎姆那喝グ
I must do just that.
回森林Y去
Hester.
我走，上我的人民
Hester!
`h督想方O法 向英政府[m@件事
Look at me.
他向我保C槟阏下t字
If I look at you, I won't be able to leave
K且公_向你道歉
Then leave.
酆秃薜木嚯x有多h
Brave the wilds!
以後我再也不受Ψ降氖`了
But Hester,
安息吧，_堋ぐ滋m因
I'm not letting you go without me.
@t字_到了一目的
They're watching us.
m然K不是
In the faraway Carolinas,
他的初衷
they were at last to find a measure ofthe happiness
我槭颤N要留在@
that hade been denied them forso long.
他接受我？被他Z服我？
My fatherdied before I reached my teens.
- ]有完美的世界，海z特 - Γ]有完美
Some say that was a punishment.
所以我要建立一H世界
My motherneverremarried norloved another.
而且榱酥
Some say that was a punishment.
我必x_@
As forme,
海z特
I do not see it that way.
Myparents shared a love like no other.
看著我
I know the spirit ofthat love lives within me.
如果看著你，我就o法x_
And will live within my children forever.
那就走吧
Who is to say what is a sin in God's eyes?
勇敢地面ν饨
不^海z特
我不你G下我一人走
他在看我
在bh的卡_R{
我的父母K於找到了
他久`了的幸福
在我不到十q的r候父H去世了
有人f，那Yλ的土P
我的母H]有再凵掀渌人
有人f，那也是λ的一N土P
可是我J
@不是土P
我的父母分享了他人所]有的
我知道那鄣木神就存在於我的心Y
K且永h存在於我的孩子心Y
l能f清，在上帝的眼中，什N是罪耗